Hi everyone, welcome back to our listening course.
In today's lesson, we're going to learn a
new question type, which is matching information.
In this lesson, we are going to review
the format and key features of matching information
questions in the IELTS listening test.
Understand and apply effective steps to answer matching
information questions by taking notes next to options
in section 2 and drawing tables to track
speakers' answers in section 3.
And finally, apply useful tips to improve accuracy
and boost your score in matching information.
By the end of this lesson, you'll feel
more confident to tackle matching information exercises in
the IELTS listening test.
So, let's get started.
First of all, we're going to look at the
requirements of matching information question type.
Firstly, this question type assesses your listening comprehension
to find specific information so that you can
choose and write the correct answer.
Secondly, this question type appears in section 2
and section 3.
The number of questions ranges from 4 to 6.
There are two formats of matching information, however,
the steps for these two are the same.
For the first format, you can see that
there is a list of options marked with
letters from A to H, and they are
placed below a heading.
The number of options is more than
that of questions, and in this example, you can
only choose each letter once.
Meanwhile, for the second format, the number of
options is less than that of the questions,
so you may use each of the letters
more than once.
Whenever you encounter matching information in section 2,
you should take notes next to the options.
If you see this question type in section
3, you should draw a table to take
notes.
The number of columns corresponds to
the number
of speakers.
You can easily realize that this strategy is
the same as what we do with multiple
choice questions that we learned before.